"妙警贼探" 前情提要...
Previously on White Collar...
Curtis Hagen今天被提前释放了
Curtis Hagen was granted early release from prison today.
Mosconi法典
The Mosconi Codex.
你让我冒着进监狱的风险去偷一本破书?
You want me to risk jail for a little light reading?
这是特别探员David Siegel
Special Agent David Siegel.
你一定是我的新负责人了
You must be my new handler.
确实
Must be.
Teddy Winters这个名字有印象吗?
Does the name Teddy Winters mean anything to you?
他们找到我了
They found me.
最起码你不用再进监狱了
Well, we kept you out of prison.
是的 为此我付出了所有
Yeah, that cost me everything.
给你法典
The Codex.
我们的合作挺顺利的
This relationship is working wonderfully.
- 什么时候是个头?  - 等到我拿到我想要的时候
- When does it end?  - When I get what I want.
我们会找出来凶手的 Neal
We'll find out who did this, Neal.
我保证
I promise.
他叫David Siegel
David Siegel.
在Bushwick区的Linden街和中央大道的交界被发现
Found on the corner of Linden and Central in Bushwick.
死因是胸部中枪
Cause of death was a gunshot wound to the sternum.
当场失血过多死亡
He bled out instantly.
现场我们找到了一个弹壳
We retrieved a shell casing from the scene.
是9毫米口径的史密斯维森39手枪的
9-millimeter caliber round from a Smith & Wesson 39 series.
这张截图来自周围的交通录像
This image was taken from a traffic cam in the area.
画面上的人物身份还没确定
The subject is still unidentifiable.
15天已经过去了
15 days have passed,
我们还是毫无头绪
And we are no closer to figuring out who did this and why.
有些人认为Siegel探员
The working theory stands that Agent Siegel was a victim
是街头行凶的无辜受害者
of an indiscriminate mugging gone wrong.
他的钱包和手枪还没有找到
His wallet and firearm are still missing.
我们部门要竭尽全力
Our division has dedicated all of its resources
调查此案
to this investigation.
但实际上 我们还有
But the truth is we had caseloads beforehand,
更紧急的案子要处理
and those caseloads still need to be resolved.
所以联合行动小组不会解散
So the joint operation center will remain in this building,
有一组探员会继续调查这个案子
And a team of agents will continue to pursue all leads.
其余人手会被分配到别的案子
The remainder of you will resume your active assignments.
纪念David Siegel最好的方式
The best way we can honor David Siegel
就是做好我们的工作
is by doing our jobs.
想要找我谈谈的人可以随时过来
Counseling remains available to anyone who still needs to talk.
散会
That's all.
你还好吧?
You okay?
嗯 我很好 怎么了?
Yeah. I am. What's going on?
你知道Caffrey现在的情况吗?
You got any updates on Caffrey's status?
他还被软禁在家
His house arrest is still in effect.
嗯 如果你还想雇佣他
Yeah, well, he can't stay there forever
可不能让他永远待在家里
if you're gonna use him.
他需要一个负责人
He needs a handler.
啊 晚安
Ah, bonsoir.
你怎么穿着浴袍?
What's with the bathrobe?
客房的水压太低
The water pressure's weak in the guest room.
所以我借用了一下你的浴室
I needed to borrow your shower.
你要在这里住多久?
How much longer are you staying here?
直到我找到了稳定的经济来源
Just until I get myself on some financially secure footing.
我可以在阳台把自己吹干吗?
Okay if I air dry on the terrace?
不 Moz 我怎么才能帮你
No, Moz. Tell me how I can help.
那家伙夺走了我的一切
Big brother burned through all of my resources.
安全屋没有了 钱也没有了
No safe houses, no capital.
更糟的是 联邦调查局
What's worse, the Federal Bureau of Invasion
把你困在了这个密不透风的狗窝里
has confined you to this impenetrable dog pound.
- 这是我家  - 宽敞明亮的监狱
- It's my apartment.  - A sublimely spacious cell.
所以你就是我的狱友了?
Does that make you my cellmate?
我更喜欢"监狱俏佳人"这个说法
I prefer the term "mis-incarcerated."
听起来像是你赢了监狱选美比赛
That sounds like you just won a prison pageant.
首先 我确实能赢 其次 我会再想个名字
A, I could. B, I'll think of a better term.
还在研究法典?
Still working on the Codex?
我不想让自己胡思乱想
I'm trying to keep my mind occupied.
不管用的
And it's not working.
Siegel总是浮现在我的脑海
I can't stop thinking about Siegel.
我一直在想他的死是不是我造成的
Can't stop wondering if it was my fault in any way.
- 可能Hagen...  - 别说了
- If Hagen somehow...  - Stop right there.
尸体是在Bushwick区被发现的
The body was found in Bushwick.
我和Hagen几小时前在那里见过面
That's where Hagen and I met a few hours earlier.
这不是巧合
It's not a coincidence.
巧合是命运之神最喜欢的把戏
Coincidence is fate's favorite tool.
因为你不知道是谁干的
You're condemning yourself
所以就在责怪自己
because there's no one else to blame.
我被困在这里 什么也做不了
I can't do anything while I'm stuck here.
如果有新的负责人
I'd be better off with a new handler
或是回监狱里也比这样好
or even thrown back in prison.
猫咪探长可不会让你回去的
The Suit will never let that happen.
有新任务?
New assignment?
部门需要破几起案子
The department needs a few wins right now.
所以你就把我叫来了?
Is that why you called me in?
- 我们要开始工作吧  - 我们?
- We're going back to work.  - We?
Peter 谢谢 但你不必为我做这么多
Oh, Peter, thank you, but you don't have to do that for me.
我是特别探员主管
I'm ASAC.
这里我说的算 我决定
I make decisions around here, and I've decided
我们要提高办案效率
that I'm going to actively pursue investigations.
- 就是这样  - 从哪个案子开始?
- That's what we do.  - Where do we start?
- 金融诈骗案  - 能不能换一个?
- Accounting scam.  - Can we start over?
你没得选 我来选
You don't get to choose. I choose.
我们的第一个案子应该选个好的
Our first case should be a good one.
这个就不错
This is a good one.
- 看看这个...  - 我要睡着了
- Now, look here...  - I just fell asleep.
放开我 我愿意合作
Don't grab me. I'm cooperating.
老实点 否则我就给你戴上手铐
Well, calm down, or I'm gonna throw you in cuffs.
嘿 怎么回事?
Hey, what's going on?
刚才他来到大厅
Guy strolled into the lobby two minutes ago.
说想和联邦调查局的人谈谈
Said he needs to talk to the FBI.
这是在他身上发现的
Found this on him.
我要自首
I need to confess to a crime.
这个案件貌似不错
Looks like it is gonna be a good one.
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 。沫
时间轴: pisces夜
翻译: 初见 伊娃 花孔雀 爱鼠影 捞小盐
校对: 爱鼠影
妙警贼探 第五季第4集
Nate Griffith 从1998年开始频繁进出拘留所
Nate Griffith. In and out of lockup since '98.
你早就想抢劫银行了 对吧?
Liked to knock off banks for a while there, didn't you?
那是很久之前的了 好吧?
That was a long time ago, okay?
我当时有债要还 最后还清了
I had dues to pay, and I paid 'em.
我一直想做回好人
Mm-hmm. I've been trying to do right
为了我的家庭
by my family ever since.
- 你的家庭  - 我有一个儿子
- Your family.  - I've got a son.
叫Andrew 他... 他七岁了
Andrew. He's... he's seven.
你快告诉我整个案件吧
Why don't you walk me through this?
好 好
Okay, okay.
我之前听说过这个在曼哈顿的证券保险库
So I'd heard about this securities vault in Manhattan
可能有200万现金
that supposedly had 2 million in cash in it.
谁告诉你的?
Who told you about it?
只是听来的 不知道
Just heard. I don't know.
你越隐瞒 就越...
Look, the more you withhold...
我发誓 没有隐瞒
I'm not trying to, I swear.
公司的名字是什么?
What's the name of the company?
是Kaplan安保公司
It's Kaplan Securities.
我... 我先搞清楚怎么绕开保护系统
So I... I figured out how to bypass the lock system
在大厦后面
in the rear of the building.
然后直奔保险库那 席卷一空
I just went straight to the vault, and I cleaned it out.
你用什么破解保险库?
What did you use to crack the vault?
我觉得我有密码
I think I had the combination.
你觉得?
You think?
听着 我是在说实话
Look, I'm telling you the truth.
好 你要明白
All right, look, you gotta understand,
这件事对我来说... 就像一场噩梦
this whole thing... it's like some sort of bad dream.
它只是零零星星地浮现在我眼前
It's only coming back to me in bits and pieces.
但我知道不能这样下去
But all I know is that I couldn't stop.
剩下的钱在哪?
Where was the rest of that money?
在... 在中央总部的一个柜子里
It's... it's in Grand Central in a locker, um...
柜子编号是941
in number 941.
密码
Combination.
你听着 这不是在玩
Yeah, see, this isn't a game.
算上你的前科 你要呆上10年监狱
With your priors, you're looking at ten years.
我知道
I know that.
一个钟头之前 我在去中央的路上
Look, an hour ago, I was walking to Grand Central
拿剩下的钱 然后我就...
to get the rest of the cash, and I just...
一直回想自己的所作所为
I kept thinking about what I'd done,
我违背了对自己和家人的承诺
how I'd broken that promise to myself and my family.
突然... 我被一辆不知从哪来的出租车撞到了
And then bam... I get hit by this cab, outta nowhere.
伤到头了
That's how I got this.
这是一个警钟
Look, it was a wake-up call.
如果我继续重操旧业下去
I cannot set a good example for my son
就无法给儿子树立一个好榜样
if all I'm gonna do is relapse.
我们在Griffith的包里找到的... 这可以解释他的行为
We found those in Griffith's bag... could explain his behavior.
他还有各色的药丸
He's got a pill for every color of the rainbow.
相呐斯 镇静剂 安定药...
Xanax, valium, ativan...
而且是高剂量的
Heavy doses too,
都是同一个精神科医生开的
all authorized by the same psychiatrist.
Mara Summers医生
Dr. Mara Summers.
来 喝点东西
Here. Drink this.
谢谢
Thanks.
你看上去和那些人不一样
You don't seem like those other guys.
因为我不是他们啊
That's 'cause I'm not.
其实 我以前和你很像
In fact, I used to be a lot like you.
你也打劫过银行?
You robbed banks?
我犯了很多错
I did a lot of things.
关键是我最后改过自新了
The point is I was able to turn myself around.
正如你正在做的 你可以和我实话实说
Just like you're trying to do. You can be straight with me.
你还有什么漏掉的吗?
Is there anything else you remember?
我知道你想帮我
I know you're trying to help me,
但我已经坦白说完了 Caffrey先生
but I honestly can't, Mr. Caffrey.
别再叫我Caffrey先生了
Don't ever call me Mr. Caffrey.
叫我Neal 来吧
It's Neal. Come on.
好的 继续找 20分钟后汇报
All right, keep looking. Update me in 20.
我派了一个团队去检查中央的保险柜
I sent a team to check the lockers at Grand Central.
那里什么都没有
There's nothing there.
现在变得越来越奇怪了
This gets stranger by the minute.
我不喜欢这样
I don't like it.
是吗?
Really?
一个人拿着一堆现金走进联邦调查局
Guy walks into the FBI with stacks of cash
然后求你抓他啊
and begs you to cuff him.
- 我以为那是你的兴奋点  - 我没有兴奋点
- I'd think that was your catnip.  - I don't have catnip.
- 每个人都有兴奋点 不是吗?  - 你的是什么?
- Oh, everybody has catnip. Yeah?  - What's yours?
"真实主妇"秀
Real Housewives.
多多益善
Can't get enough.
钱上都有Griffith的手指印
Money has Griffith's prints all over it.
我们看看这些序号
We're running the serial numbers.
你发现什么了?
What do you have?
每张纸币左上角的质地摸起来不一样
Texture feels funny in the top-left corner of every bill.
我要再仔细看看
I'm gonna need a closer look.
做过标记的
Marked bills.
本来有可能用于地下交易或结算
Cash could've been used in a controlled buy or payoff.
或者另有来源
Or it's from another score.
对 有没有可能这家伙偷的钱
Yeah, is it possible our guy stole money
本来就是其他人偷来的?
that was already stolen?
我觉得Neal和我该亲自去检查那个保险库
I think Neal and I should check out that vault.
联邦调查局的 要见你们经理
FBI here to see the manager.
他在那
That's him there.
自己熟悉下数据库
Familiarize yourself with the database
从你桌面上的客户名册开始
starting with the client roster on your desktop.
然后 要按照日期和时间
After that, I want you to categorize
对本月的财务方案进行分类
this month's financial packages by date and time.
- 你都清楚了吗?  - 清楚了
- Are you getting all of this?  - Yes, sir.
很好 那回到自己的座位吧
Good. Back to your desk, then.
抱歉 先生们
Ah. Apologies, gentlemen.
他第一天上班 我能做点什么吗?
It's his first day. How can I help you?
我是特别探员Peter Burke
Special agent Peter Burke,
这是我同事Neal Caffrey
and this is my coworker Neal Caffrey.
你好
How you doing?
我们是来调查上周的盗窃事件的
We're here about the break-in that happened last week.
盗窃?
Break-in?
今早一个出了名的重罪犯去我们办公室
This morning a known felon walked into our offices
承认自己洗劫一空了四号保险库
to confess to emptying the contents of vault number four.
不可能
Oh, impossible.
我们没有客人上报失窃
None of our clients have reported anything missing,
我也保证我们的安全系统是顶尖的
and I assure you our security is top-notch.
其实你还可以升级下
Actually, you could use an upgrade.
你们保险库的U.I.安全许可级别仅是一级
The U.I. Approval on your vaults is class I.
也就是说30分钟之内就可以撬开
That means they can be breached in 30 minutes or less.
当然也需要合适的切割轮
I mean, you need the right cutting wheel
和硬质合金钻头
and carbide drill, of course.
- 我建议升级到三级  - 可以看下保险库吗?
- My advice, go class III.  - Could I see the vault?
我们严格保护
Uh, we're very protective
客户的财产和隐私
about our clients' possessions and anonymity.
没有搜查令的话
Without a warrant,
我只能提供这些信息
this is all the info I can give you.
如果还有其他问题 请随时联系
Feel free to call if you have further questions.
再见 先生们
Gentlemen.
如果保险库里的钱是非法获取的
Well, if the cash in the vault was illegally obtained,
无论谁是户主
it makes sense that whoever owns it
都不会上报失窃 这讲得过去
Wouldn't want to report it missing.
除非他们也想进监狱
Unless they want to go to prison too.
但这些都是推测的
But this is all speculative.
不足以申请搜查令
It's not good enough for a warrant.
Louis啊!
Louis!
如果我们看不了保险库
If we can't get a look at the vault,
也许可以找下户主是谁的
maybe we can find out who owns it.
Louis啊!
Louis!
谢谢
Thank you.
有办法吗?
What's the play?
看来Kaplan安保公司今天会有
Well, Kaplan Securities is going to have
更多新员工了
more than one new employee today.
- 那个宣传册还在吗?  - 在
- You still have that brochure?  - Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
好
Okay.
小心你的手指 Peter...
Watch your fingers. Peter...
你以前肯定做过
You've done this before.
即黏胶水
Instant glue.
先凑合用一下吧
Well, it'll do in a pinch.
你吓到我了
You frighten me.
事实上 往往你才是吓人的那个
Actually, you're usually the frightening one.
你钱包里有照片吗?
You have any pictures in your wallet?
需要帮忙吗?
Can I help you?
我是Eric Roberts 你的主管
Eric Roberts. I'm your supervisor.
Epstein先生没提过你
Mr. Epstein didn't say anything about you.
- 我要打个电话...  - 不是吧 只有你和Epstein先生
- I have to call and...  - What, you and Mr. Epstein
在这上班吗?
are the only employees here?
我知道你还要处理那些财务方案
Look, I know you have those financial packages to work on,
但这位贵宾更重要
but this man takes precedence.
Wilcox先生是首屈一指的进出口商人
Mr. Wilcox is a premier importer and exporter
在东岸可是叱咤风云
up and down the east coast,
他想开个账户
and he'd like to open an account.
他会的
He would.
现在填写申请书
That means start-up papers.
规定不是这样的 我们有系统流程
That isn't protocol. We have a system.
- 你最好给我搞定  - 必须的 Wilcox先生
- You better make this work.  - Very good, Mr. Wilcox.
我来这五年了
I've been here for five years,
你只是初来乍到
You've been here for five seconds.
赶快准备文件
Start up paperwork.
楼下大厅左边第三个办公室
Third office, down the hall, left-hand side.
好 好 我很快回来
Of course. Of course. I'll be right back.
好的 四号保险库
All right. Vault number four.
留意点
Keep a lookout.
好
Yeah.
严格来说我要先拿到法院指令
Technically I should get a court order
才能操作那台电脑
to go through that computer.
幸亏你的线人有别的办法
Well, good thing your CI doesn't need one.
Neal啊
Neal.
数据库里有250个客户
There are 250 clients in this database.
按照保险库编号缩小范围
Narrowing it down by vault number.
我找到了
I found it.
四号保险库
Vault number four.
真奇怪
That's strange.
不是个人注册的
It's not registered to a person.
那是什么?
To what, then?
是一间公司注册的 Niteowl控股公司
To a corporation. Niteowl Holdings.
- 谢谢  - 太感谢了 先生
- Thank you.  - Thank you very much, sir.
够了 撤吧
That's good enough. Go.
Louis啊!
Louis!
这是一间虚拟的公司
It's a dummy corp.
有人在用Noteowl公司作掩饰
Someone is using Niteowl as a front.
无论Griffith偷了谁的东西 他们的身份都隐藏得很好
Whoever Griffith stole from covered their identity nicely.
对
Mm-hmm.
大伙们 我找到那些带记号纸币的线索了
Gentlemen, I got a lead on those marked bills.
两个月之前 曼哈顿一辆运钞车被洗劫一空了
Two months ago, a Manhattan mutual truck was cleaned out.
所以现在银行规定在所有纸币上做记号
Now it's the bank's policy to mark all currency
以防发生盗窃
in case any kind of theft occurs.
纽约警局找到了嫌疑人 只是不能定他罪
NYPD had a suspect, just couldn't nail him.
Shane Jacoby 有过殴打他人的前科
Shane Jacoby. Priors for assault.
他貌似是Niteowl控股公司的执行总裁
And likely CEO of Niteowl Holdings.
Griffith和Jacoby互不相识
So Griffith and Jacoby don't know each other,
但他们是有关联的 怎么关联?
but they're linked. How?
我估计已经找到关联点了
I might've found that link.
Shane Jacoby接受了一个法庭命令的治疗
Shane Jacoby received a court-ordered treatment
和治疗Griffith的是同一个精神科医生
from a psychiatrist who prescribed Griffith his meds.
Mara Summers医生
Dr. Mara Summers.
冲动控制障碍有五个常见阶段
There are five common stages to ICD,
始于冲动 终于愧疚
Beginning with the impulse and ending with guilt
或毫无愧疚
or lack thereof.
最后这一阶段的...
It is that final...
真是个有意思的专业领域
This is an interesting area of expertise.
是啊 难怪Griffith找上了她
Yeah, I can see why Griffith went to her.
我发现那些为自己的行为
I found the patient who experiences guilt
感到愧疚的病人 更容易回归
from his actions is most likely to fall back
初始的摧毁性模式
into the original destructive pattern.
这是我在研究过程中 与我合作的多名改造罪犯的
This is generally the case with the bulk of reformed criminals
普遍情况
I've worked with in my studies.
明天的课上我们会详细讨论
More on that in tomorrow's lecture.
感谢大家的参与
Thank you all for coming.
她的一些客户具有犯罪倾向
She's got clients prone to commit crimes,
她能进入他们的大脑
and she's got access to their heads.
然后控制他们
She could be manipulating them.
亦或她只是在做本职工作
Or she could just be doing her job.
想弄明白只有一个办法
Only one way to find out.
- 讲得太棒了 谢谢您  - 谢谢
- Excellent, thank you.  - Thank you.
Summers医生
Dr. Summers.
抱歉 你是...
I'm sorry, you are...
我叫Neal Caffrey
My name's Neal Caffrey.
我是个已定罪的重刑犯 我需要您的帮助
I'm a convicted felon, and I need your help.
不得不说 您对于冲动控制障碍的研究令人惊叹
Your work and research on ICD is impressive, to say the least.
我对该领域很有兴趣
I have a predilection for its study.
哦 Summers医生 这就是我和您说的人 Peter
Oh, Dr. Summers, this is the man I told you about, Peter.
我的假释官
My parole officer.
你看管Caffrey先生多久了?
How long have you been keeping an eye on Mr. Caffrey?
- 可以说一直都是吧  - 我得把话说明白了
- Eternally, some might say.  - I have to be honest.
我与绝大多数改造罪犯的合作都是无偿的
Most of my work with reformed criminals is pro bono.
但现在我实在没时间
Right now I simply don't have time
接新的病人
to take on any new patients.
我并不是想要您免费服务
Oh, I'm not asking you for a free session.
- 我收费很贵  - 这不是问题
- I'm expensive.  - Won't be a problem.
Peter 你何不向Summers医生简要介绍下我?
Peter, would you mind briefly giving Dr. Summers my resume?
简要介绍? 好吧
Briefly? Right.
Neal因伪造债券而被定罪
Well, Neal's been convicted of bond forgery.
同时 他牵涉了超过四十桩
He's also been implicated in over four dozen
艺术品伪造案
works of counterfeit art.
另外他还是数起备受关注的
And there's also the fact that he's still a suspect
联邦案件的嫌疑人
in several ongoing high-profile federal investigations.
- 具体是什么案件?  - 随便说 都有
- For what, exactly?  - Pick something.
总而言之 钱对我这种人来说可不是问题
Bottom line, money may not be a problem for a guy like me.
这话我没听见
I didn't hear that.
明天下午1点 来我办公室
My office, 1:00 p.m. Tomorrow.
很期待与您合作
I look forward to working with you.
干得好
Nice job.
两个罪犯 同一个精神病医生
Two criminals, same psychiatrist.
我觉得比起客户 她更关心她自己
I think she's looking after herself more than her clientele.
也许她操纵一个客户
It's possible she had a patient
偷了另一个客户的钱
steal from another patient,
但我不明白她怎么办到的
But it's the how of all this that bothers me.
你没法在一个人不知道的情况下
You can't put the idea of a heist in someone's head
把抢劫的主意塞进他脑袋里去
without them knowing about it.
Peter 这没什么奇怪的
Peter, it's not that odd.
在1到10中间挑一个数
Think of a number between one and ten.
不 我讨厌你玩这招
No, I hate it when you do this.
就挑一个数
Just think of a number.
2 3 4 5 随便哪个
Two, three, four, five, whatever.
- 想好了?  - 嗯
- You got it?  - Yup.
现在大声说出来
Now say it out loud in your head.
"7 7 7" 就像这样
"seven, seven, seven," for example.
我就知道你想干嘛 Neal 才不是7
I know what you're doing. It's not seven, Neal.
当然不是 是9
No, it's nine.
好吧 你怎么办到的?
Okay, how did you do that?
在让你挑一个数之前
Before I asked you to think of a number,
我说话时用了 "奇" 字
I used the word "odd" in a sentence.
所以通常来说 你会选一个奇数
So naturally, you'll choose an odd number.
- 接着?  - 接着我通过
- Then?  - Then I made your mind
大声念 "2 3 4 5" 以及 "7"
subtly cross off options by saying
令你无意识地排除了这些选择
"two, three, four, five" and "seven" aloud.
只剩下1和9
Which leaves the numbers one and nine.
而没人会选1的 因为这太显眼
And nobody chooses one because it's too obvious.
9比较不起眼 所以你选了它
Nine is more obscure, so that's what you go with.
很好 但你想说明什么
That's good. Okay, but the point of all this.
在不到20秒的时间里
In less than 20 seconds,
我就让你选了我要的数字
I got you to the number I wanted.
再想想Griffith和Summers
Now think of Griffith and Summers.
有了那么长时间的影响
With that much time and influence,
她定能叫他言听计从
She could make him do anything she wanted.
这人是无辜的
This guy's innocent.
但这些不够 Neal
I need more, Neal.
当你和Summers会面时 找出她或Griffith
When you're with Summers, find something tangible
与Jacoby的钱有联系的具体证据
that links her or Griffith to Jacoby's cash.
那你呢?
What are you gonna do?
我拿到了Shane Jacoby的工作地址
I've got Shane Jacoby's work address.
我去看看能否找到他和Niteowl控股公司
I'm gonna go down there and see if I can find a connection
之间的关系
between him and Niteowl Holdings.
Neal 要当心
Neal, be careful.
我可不想这个精神病医生入侵你的头脑
I do not want this therapist getting inside your head.
拜托 我的头脑坚不可摧
Please. I'm a wall.
真的?
Really?
告诉我 你想要
Tell me, what kind of change
改变生活的哪个方面?
are you looking to make with your life?
大概是想恢复正常吧
I guess I'm looking for some normalcy.
谢谢
Thank you.
那如果这不可能呢?
And what if that's not possible?
听起来不怎么鼓励人啊
That doesn't sound very encouraging.
我不是来鼓励你的
I'm not here to encourage you.
我是来帮助你发掘
I'm here to help you discover
真正的自我 这样你才能接受它
the truth about yourself, so you can accept it.
接受自己无法恢复正常的事实?
I have to accept that I can't be normal?
你太有意思了 以至于无法变得正常
You're too interesting to be normal.
什么让我变得有意思?
What makes me so interesting?
你那永远要成为房间里
Your pathological assumption that you need to be
最聪明的人的病理假设
the smartest person in the room at all times.
或许你才是做出假设的人
Maybe you're the one assuming things.
就满墙的证书而言
According to all these diplomas on your wall,
你比我聪明多了 不过话说回来
you're a lot smarter than me, but then again,
那些只是一纸空文 而非实际能力
those are just papers, not people.
你觉得你擅长和人打交道吗?
Do you think you're good with people?
- 比不上你  - 这是我的工作
- No more than you.  - It's my job.
也是我的
Mine too.
你的手段很强势
You have an aggressive approach.
而你已经开始防守了
And you're already withholding.
但这很正常
But that's natural.
我们需要更多地互相了解 以建立信任
We need to know one another better to build trust.
你觉得我不够诚实?
You don't think I'm being honest?
不够
Not yet.
但你会的
But you will be.
迟早的事
In time.
Jacoby先生!
Mr. Jacoby!
Peter Burke 联邦调查局的
Peter Burke, FBI.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
我想和你谈谈
I'd like to talk to you
你在Kaplan安保公司的金库
regarding your vault at Kaplan Security.
我不知道你在说什么
Don't know what you're talking about.
好吧 那就换个说法
Okay, let's try that again.
今年9月4日你在哪里?
Where were you on september 4th of this year?
纽约警局想把货车的事归在我头上
NYPD tried to pin that truck on me.
但他们没有证据 你也一样
They had nothing. Same as you.
好吧 好吧 别激动
All right, all right, calm down.
我不喜欢被指控
I don't like accusations.
那你就不该犯罪
Well, then you shouldn't be a criminal.
我尤其不喜欢说我犯罪这个指控
I especially don't like that accusation.
这不是指控 这是事实
It's not an accusation. It's a fact.
我看了你的警方档案 加重伤害罪
Read your rap sheet. Aggravated assault.
你打断了一个保安的鼻子
You busted the nose of a security guard
以及三根手指
and three of his fingers.
我不再是那样的人了
That's not who I am anymore.
和我讲讲Niteowl控股公司
Tell me about Niteowl Holdings.
也没听说过
Never heard of that either.
你找错人了 Burke探员
You're talking to the wrong guy, Agent Burke.
值得怀疑 不过最后一个问题
Well, that's doubtful, but one more question.
法院指定你和Mara Summers医生间的愤怒管理课程
How did those court-ordered anger management sessions go
进行得如何了?
with Dr. Mara Summers?
要么找点来由把我关进去 要么就让我走
Either take me in on something, or let me get on with my day.
帽子不错
Nice hat.
你读过布鲁克林寄宿高中
You went to Brooklyn residential high.
玩什么体育项目?
What sport did you play?
摔跤 完了没有?
All state in wrestling. Are we done?
唔 没呢
Mm, not quite,
不过你可以走了 Jacoby先生
but you can get on with your day now, Mr. Jacoby.
哦 你知道吗? Kaplan安保公司的金库
Oh, you know that vault that was in Kaplan Security,
就是那个装了200万现金的?
the one with the $2 million cash in it?
它已经空了
It's all gone now.
不过你肯定知道了
But you knew that.
或者你不知道
Or you didn't know that.
好了 现在你知道了 祝你今天愉快
Well, now you do. Have a good day.
- 工作  - 受限制
- Job.  - Confined.
- 嫉妒  - 软弱
- Jealousy.  - Weak.
- 金钱  - 支撑
- Money.  - Prop.
- 女人  - 希望
- Women.  - Hope.
- Peter  - 杰出
- Peter.  - Worthy.
- 偷窃  - 胜任
- Theft.  - Capable.
- 被捕  - 糟了
- Caught.  - Oops.
你得出什么结论了吗?
You make something from that?
下诊断还太早
It's too early to diagnose.
但你还是有了点想法
But you've got something.
你的回答总体来说很有意思
Your answers are unique in summation.
我保证我能应付 医生
I assure you I can handle it, doctor.
你的行为具有反社会倾向
Your behavior is sociopathic.
什么?
I'm sorry?
你专注于观察他人
You work on perception, the perception of others.
体会他们的感受
How you think they'll feel.
这对你行为和思维的影响
This influences your actions and thoughts
远远大于你自身情绪的影响
more so than your own emotions.
欺诈与操纵是紊乱的
Deceit and manipulation are the essential characteristics
两大特质... 而你二者兼备
of the disorder... You excel at both.
欺诈与操纵适用于
Deceit and manipulation are generalities
任何一个说谎者
that can apply to anyone who lies,
而任何人都会说谎 包括你 Summers医生
And everyone lies, including you, Dr. Summers.
或许是的
That may be true,
但并非所有人都能相信自己的谎言
but not everyone believes their own lies.
我为什么要欺骗自己?
Why would I delude myself?
因为你不希望别人看到你的弱点
Because you don't want anyone to see your vulnerabilities.
你不觉得我自信
I don't strike you as confident.
自信的人会承认缺点
Confident people admit to their flaws.
而你不会
You don't.
你只是一笑了之
Instead you smile a lot.
你很自信 那你的缺点是什么?
You're confident. What are your flaws?
我可以很强势 这你之前就提到了
I can be aggressive, like you pointed out earlier.
紧张时我会抠指甲
I also pick at my nails when I get nervous.
没有人是完美的
Nobody's perfect.
确实
Precisely.
一个人越是追求完美
The harder a person fights to be perfect,
就越是压抑本我
the more he suppresses his true nature.
我...
I'm...
我已经改变了
I'm reformed.
真的吗?
Are you?
一个人开始做好事
Just because a person starts doing good things
并不意味着就不做坏事了
doesn't mean he wants to stop doing bad things.
当然不是
Of course not.
因为每个人在人生的某一时刻
Because everyone has done something bad
都做过坏事 哪怕你也是
at some point in their life, even you.
现在说的不是我
This is not about me.
我觉得骗子都能承认自己的缺点
I thought confident people could admit to their flaws.
- 你在扯开话题...  - 你也是
- You're redirecting...  - So are you.
因为你感觉不舒服
Because you're uncomfortable.
你不认为我能改变
You don't think that I can change.
我是在问 你是否想改变
I'm asking if you really want to.
抱歉 我感觉不舒服
I'm sorry. I don't feel well.
我说过 试着放松点
Like I said, try to relax.
我还要问你几个问题
I have a few more questions for you.
怎么回事?
What's happening?
我们正在使用一种新的疗法
We're using a new form of therapy.
- 你给我下了药  - 我在帮你
- You drugged me.  - I'm helping you.
我在帮你
I'm helping you.
我只要你跟我说真话
What I want is for you to simply tell me the truth
你是谁 是做什么的
about who you are, what you really do,
为什么要来这儿
and why you're really here.
你准备好 我们就开始吧
I am ready to begin when you are.
嘿 Neal
Neal?
你没事吧?
You okay?
怎么回事?
What happened?
我们用了催眠技术
We began to practice hypnotherapy technique.
你睡了好一会儿了
You were out for quite some time.
你醒不过来
You had trouble waking.
真的吗?
Are you sure?
也许你该吃点东西
Perhaps you could use something to eat
或者喝杯水
or a glass of water.
不用 我得走了
No, I should go.
要我帮你叫辆出租车吗?
Would you like me to call you a cab?
不 不用
No. No.
我没事
I'm fine.
- Peter  - 进来
- Peter.  - Yeah.
在布鲁克林居民档案馆找到这个
Got this from Brooklyn residential's archives.
Jacoby毕业那年的
The year Jacoby graduated.
就是他
That's him.
这是赢了全美摔跤比赛的猫头鹰队
That's the team that won All State. The Owls.
我一看到帽子就认出了这个吉祥物
I remembered the mascot when I saw his hat.
猫头鹰队夺冠那一年
Championship year for the Owls,
队长就是Shane Jacoby
led by team captain Shane Jacoby.
他以攻击性的击倒
Known for his aggressive takedowns
以及深夜训练出名
and late-night practices,
于是有了"夜猫头鹰"的昵称
earning him the nickname the Night Owl.
这就是他和Niteowl控股公司的联系
And there is our link to Niteowl Holdings.
打电话给纽约警局 把这位怀旧的朋友带来问话
Call NYPD, have our nostalgic friend brought in.
听着挺不错的
Sounds good.
Summers识破我了
Summers is onto me.
你在说什么? 怎么盯上的?
What are you talking about? How?
我不知道 但她给我下药了
I don't know, but she dosed me with something.
她想办法让我开口 我根本不记得自己说了什么
She got me to talk, I can't even remember what I said to her.
我晕过去了
I passed out.
你知道是什么药吗?
Do you know what it was?
我完全不知道
No, I have no idea.
她肯定是掺进了我喝的水里
She must've slipped it into my water.
好吧 我们得尽快让你做一个毒样检查
Okay, we're gonna get you a tox screen ASAP.
Peter 如果有结果
Peter, if that's the case,
我们就有足够的证据立刻逮捕Summers
we have enough to arrest Summers right now.
如果我们现在逮捕她 很有可能就没法
If we bring her in now, there's a good chance we won't
找回她偷走的钱 就还不了Griffith清白
find the money she stole. Griffith won't be cleared.
Griffith 她就是这么识破你的
Griffith. That's how she made you.
没错 我又见了Summers医生
Yeah, I saw Dr. Summers again.
你告诉她我是个联邦调查局探员
And you told her I was an FBI agent.
没错 还说了他是个顾问
Yeah, and he was a consultant.
你有什么目的?
What are you up to?
没目的
Nothing.
听着 我不知道你们在调查她
Look, I didn't know you were investigating her.
我怎么可能知道?
How could I have known?
听着 发生了那么多事 我必须找个人谈谈
Look, I had to talk to someone after everything that happened.
Jacoby不在他的住所和其它常去的地方
Jacoby's not at his residence or any known location.
看来他藏起来了
Looks like he went off-grid.
我们得去追踪他了
We're gonna have to track him down.
听着... 我不是故意把事情弄成这样的
Look, I... I didn't mean for any of this to happen.
你来这里 就是做了正确的事
Look, you did the right thing coming here.
只不过现在出了问题
Only after the fact.
如果我没法改变呢?
What if I can't change?
如果我这辈子就注定...
What if I can't be anything more than...
是个罪犯呢?
a criminal?
晚安 灰姑娘
Good night, Cinderella.
什么?
What?
是种药 叫"晚安 灰姑娘"
Oh, it's a drug. Good night, Cinderella.
很有可能就是Summers给你下的药
It's most likely what Summers spiked your drink with.
在里约工作的女孩子很喜欢用
Very popular with the working girls of Rio.
我听说的
I've heard stories.
你是听说的 还是试过了?
You've heard them or have them?
这有区别吗?
What's the difference?
区别就在于你一直在用我的毛巾
The difference is you've been using my towels.
你在我冰箱里放了什么?
What did you put in my fridge?
我做了Hongeo
Oh, I made some Hongeo.
- 能拿出来吗?  - 这是道美食
- Can you please unmake it?  - It's a delicacy.
这是条腐烂的韩国鱼
It's rotted Korean skate fish.
配韩国泡菜和米酒最合适
Fantastic with, um, kimchi and rice wine.
我以为你想尝尝的
I thought you'd like some.
好吧 如果你还想住这儿
All right, if you are gonna live here,
就别再做菜了
you can no longer cook here.
你是在嫉妒我优越的味蕾吗?
Jealous of my refined palate?
我怀疑你还有没有味蕾
I am surprised that one even exists.
接着说"晚安 灰姑娘"
Good night, Cinderella. You were saying.
这药混合了γ-羟丁酸 氯胺酮和氟甲硝基安定
Oh, it's a combination of GHB, ketamine, and flunitrazepam.
那些姑娘喜欢给客人下药
The girls give it to their johns,
在药效期间 他们就会言听计从
and then they do whatever they want while under the influence.
他们会把钱都交出来
Empty out their bank accounts,
把车钥匙拱手让人
hand them the keys to their car.
大多数人第二天根本不记得发生了什么
Next day, most guys don't recall anything happening.
他们只会将这个归结为玩得太过火了
They just chalk it up to having too much fun.
你觉得Summers知道这些吗?
And you think Summers knows about this?
学药理学的就都知道
Well, anything's possible with pharmacology.
她是个精神病医生
She's a psychiatrist.
在这个领域是有学位的
She does have a degree in the field.
她在治疗很多所谓的罪犯
She's working with so many so-called criminals,
完全可以学会一两招
she could've picked up a trick or two.
我得弄清楚都告诉她什么
I need to find out what I told her.
我可能什么都说了
I could've told her everything.
不仅仅是这个案子的事情
And not just about this case.
万一我跟她说了Hagen的事怎么办?
What if I said something about Hagen?
- 或者是Siegel的事?  - 有个办法能弄清楚
- Or Siegel?  - There's a way to find out.
RMT疗法
RMT.
- 寻回记忆疗法  - 你了解多少?
- Recovered memory therapy.  - What do you know about it?
很简单
It's simple.
我喝多酒之后 就会忘事儿
I drink too much wine, I forget things.
为了想起那些事情 我就再多喝点酒
In order to remember them, I drink more wine.
我知道你的确是这么干的
I'm sure you do.
为了寻回记忆 通常情况下最有效的办法
To recover a memory, it's often most effective
就是重新创造出和失去记忆时
to recreate the conditions one was experiencing
完全一样的状态
at the time of that memory's loss.
所以你想说
So what you're saying
我得回那鬼地方一次?
is I need to go back down the rabbit hole?
听着 就算我打算用这个办法
Look, even if I were gonna consider this,
你能在大街上找到这种药吗?
would you be able to find this stuff on the street?
不 当然找不到
No, of course not.
我得帮你配一剂
I'd have to make it for you.
你确定这就是Summers用的配方?
You're sure this is the exact combination that Summers used?
非常确定
Mm, pretty sure.
人生中的必然之一
One of the few certainties in life
就是要躲开那些一尘不变的人
is that persons of certainty should certainly be avoided.
这可没让我放心
That does not make me feel better.
好吧 我的确调整了配方
Okay, I made a few modifications.
我添加了一种温和的兴奋剂 用来延迟你的视觉
I added a mild stimulant to prolong your vision quest.
很好
Great.
你在变化状态中清醒的时间越久
The more time you spend awake in this altered state,
我们的成功几率就越大
the better our chances of success.
不会有副作用
And there are no lasting effects.
没有 事实上
No, in fact you'll be
你可以完全控制自己
in complete control of your faculties,
这得归功于我添加的钾兴奋剂
Thanks to my added Potassium stimulant.
只要结束后我能醒得过来就好
As long as I wake up when it's over.
Neal 你不会有事的
Neal, you'll be fine.
我就是你的夏尔巴向导
I am your sherpa guide.
是你将要投身的
Your spirit animal
正常奇幻之旅的精神向导
for this fantastic voyage you're about to embark upon.
相信我 这就是解决办法
Trust me. This is the solution.
晚安 灰姑娘
Boa noite Cinderela.
回忆一下那间办公室
Remember the office.
形状 质感 摆设
The shapes, the textures, the view.
Summers医生就坐在你对面
Dr. Summers is sitting across from you.
她在等着你失去意识
She's waiting for you to lose your inhibitions.
她说了什么?
What is she saying?
你准备好 我们就开始吧
I'm ready to begin when you are.
深呼吸 保持冷静
Take a deep breath, and stay calm.
镇定剂药效过了之后 你不会记得自己说了什么
You won't remember what you tell me once the narcotic wears off.
她有没有问你问题?
Did she ask you any questions?
问了 她想...
Yeah, she wanted...
她想要...
she wanted to...
联邦调查局都知道了什么?
What does the FBI know?
什么都知道了
Everything.
那他们有什么证据?
What can the FBI prove?
什么都证明不了
Ah. Nothing.
你问了她问题吗?
Did you ask her any questions?
问了
Yeah.
你投了两百万 为什么?
You stole the 2 million. Why?
和你偷艺术品的动机一样
For the same reason you steal.
因为就摆在你面前
Because it was there.
这方法肯定没用
This isn't gonna work.
- 我没法好好思考  - 这就是关键
- I can't think straight.  - That's exactly the point.
要换种角度思考
Think circular.
不 我是说Summers
No, I mean Summers.
她说得没错 我没有变
She was right. I'm not reformed.
我是说 我喜欢现在的工作
I mean, I like doing the things I do.
我喜欢和Peter一起工作
You know, I like working with Peter,
也喜欢和联邦调查局合作
I like working with the FBI.
好吧 这就是迷药在发挥作用
Okay, that's simply the drugs talking.
但我也喜欢跟他们对着干
But I also like working against 'em.
我喜欢做不应该做的事情 而且也不觉得愧疚
I like doing things I shouldn't, and I don't feel guilty,
不会自责 没有其它任何感觉除了...
I don't feel remorse, I don't feel anything except...
好吧 看来兴奋剂加多了
Okay, too much stimulant.
也许你也应该喝点这个药
Maybe you should take some of the solution too.
没错 这可以让你想起来
Yeah, it could help you remember.
- 想起什么?  - 真正的你
- Remember what?  - Who you are.
你在这里做什么 Moz?
What are you doing here, Moz?
你应该在外面重建自己的生活
You should be out on the streets rebuilding yourself.
你很聪明 人缘又广
You are smart, you are resourceful.
只要没有身高要求的事情 你都能办得到
You can do anything without a height requirement.
这没那么简单
It isn't so easy.
难道警察终于把你逼到角落 打趴你了吗?
Has big brother really finally just cornered you into defeat?
我去拿纸笔 把这些都写下来
I'm gonna get a pen and write some of this down for research.
去吧
Go.
好了 我们接着...
Okay, we should take it fr...
不
Oh, no.
- Burkes  - 是Neal啊
- Burkes.  - Neal.
有什么事儿吗?
What are you doing here?
没
No.
只是有些话不说憋着难受
I just came to get some stuff off my chest.
我才七年级的时候 还什么都不懂
I was in seventh grade, I didn't know any better,
但是看到那钞票从她的包里伸出来一小截
but the money was sticking out of her purse,
"啵" 就成我的了
and boop, mine.
跟在伯利兹偷伽利多那副自画像如出一辙
It was the same thing with the Garrido self-portrait in Belize.
当然没有从钱包里抽出来那么容易
I mean, I wasn't taking that out of a purse.
那边其实是美国古董总中心
It was more like a highly secured wing
戒备异常森严的一侧
of a Central American Antiquities Center.
我是不是有点话痨?
Am I talking too much?
- 他没事吧?  - 一头雾水
- Is he okay?  - I have no idea.
我在做实验
I am conducting an experiment.
试着回忆
I am trying to remember
我当时跟Summers都说了些什么...
what I said to Summers when I was under...
这边真热
It's hot in here.
你干了什么?
What did you do?
我跟Mozzie说了 他给了我一剂药
I talked to Mozzie, and he gave me a solution,
我喝了下去
and I drank that solution.
我没听懂
I don't understand.
他在一个什么可笑的实验里给自己下了药
He drugged himself in some ridiculous experiment
来再现他都跟那个精神病医生说了什么
to recreate what he said to the psychiatrist.
Neal 你饿不饿?
Neal, are you hungry?
你看起来需要吃点东西
You look like you could use something to eat.
我现在倒是不饿
I'm actually not hungry right now,
不过要是有你做的那种美味菜鸡
but if you have any of those fantastic game hens you make,
我可以一会儿吃上一点
maybe later.
不过不要肉饼 我不大喜欢那个
Ooh, no meat loaf, though. I'm not a fan.
宝贝 让我们俩单独待一会儿好吗?
Honey, could you excuse us for a minute?
好的
Yeah.
Neal啊
Neal.
你知道Siegel怎么死的吗?
Do you know what happened to Siegel?
你没回答我 Siegel的事
You're not answering my question. Siegel.
我不知道怎么回事 而且...
I don't know what happened, and...
你瞒了我什么 Neal?
What aren't you telling me, Neal?
谢天谢地
Oh, good.
就算热爱梭罗
For the love of thoreau,
梭罗 美国作家 主张回归自然
你也不能就这么随随便便跑进树林里
you can't simply wander off into the woods like that.
嘿 Moz 你在我屋里干什么呢?
Hey, Moz. What're you doing in my house?
他像个追着断了线的气球的
He ran away like an impudent child
傻小孩儿一样跑出了屋子
chasing after an untethered balloon.
怎么回事?
What happened?
我们做了尝试 而且成功了
We tried something, and it worked.
他开始回忆起部分Summers控制住他的时候
He was starting to remember parts of the conversation
和他的对话了
when Summers had him under.
但你最多只剩大概15分钟了
But you only have about 15 minutes left, at best.
然后他就会睡着了
Then he's gonna want nap time.
好吧 来吧
All right, let's do this.
- Neal  - 嗯
- Neal.  - Yeah.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
- 闭眼  - 嗯
- Close your eyes.  - Yeah.
从你断开那里接着往下回忆
Just try to remember where you left off.
联邦调查局都知道了什么?
What does the FBI know?
Summers问我联邦调查局知道了什么
Summers asked me what the FBI knew.
她知道我们什么证据也没有
She realized we have nothing.
她接下去问了什么?
What did she ask next?
她问了...
She asked about...
Griffith的事
Griffith.
联邦调查局会起诉他吗?
Will the FBI prosecute?
很快就会的
They will soon.
非常好 Neal
That's good, Neal.
保持注意力集中
Stay focused.
然后 她站起身
After that, she stood up.
她去了哪儿?
Where did she go?
打了个电话
To make a phone call.
打给谁?
Who did she call?
我看到她打的号码了
I saw the number she dialed.
区号是212
It was a 212 area code.
有三个5...
Three fives...
零 一...
0, 1...
还有两位数字 Neal
Two more digits, Neal.
零 一...
0, 1...
八 四
8, 4.
干得漂亮
Nice work.
看看她给谁打的电话
Let's find out who she called.
我是Jacoby 有事请留言
This is Jacoby. Leave a message.
她给Shane Jacoby打的电话
She called Shane Jacoby.
Neal 我们得...
Neal, we're gonna have to...
给你拿床毯子
grab you a blanket.
我带他走
I'll take him.
什么 你要背着他吗?
What, are you gonna carry him?
我要告诉你我做了不少屈腕练习的
I'll have you know I've been doing a lot of wrist curls.
你已经帮了很多忙 我来照顾他吧
You've done plenty. I'll take care of him.
Jones 嘿
Jones. Hey.
我想明天去见Griffith
I want to see Griffith tomorrow,
你得跟我一起去
and I'm gonna need you to come with me.
现在不太方便
Now's not really a good time.
不方便也得方便
Make time.
你不认识Shane Jacoby
You don't know Shane Jacoby.
跟你们说过了 我不认识
I told you guys, no, I don't.
他倒是可能认识你
Well, he may know about you.
Summers昨天和他联系过
Summers made contact with him yesterday.
我已经把知道的都告诉你们了
I've told you everything that I can.
我... 我真的很抱歉 但你们真的得走了
I'm... I'm really sorry, guys, but you're gonna have to leave.
我得去学校接孩子
I have to pick up my kid from school.
只能追查到底了
Just had to follow up on this.
我们会尽力弄清怎么回事的
We're doing everything we can to figure out what's going on here.
只要你不犯我们
You don't waste our time,
Griffith先生 我们绝不犯你
Mr. Griffith, we won't waste yours.
- 我说的都是实话  - 我相信你
- I'm telling you the truth.  - I believe you.
既然你要去接孩子
And I know that you have to see your kid,
那我们就先走了
so we'll be on our way.
但要是出了什么事
But if anything should come up,
联系我们就好 听见了吗?
you make sure you call us. You got it?
嗯 嗯 听见了
Yeah, yeah. Got it.
保持联络
We'll be in touch.
好了 他们走了
All right, they're gone.
爸爸 怎么回事?
Daddy, what's happening?
没事的 宝贝
It's okay, buddy.
滚开
Back up.
是啊 他会没事的
Yeah, he'll be okay.
只要你告诉我你把我的200万藏哪儿去了
As soon as you tell me where you stashed my 2 million.
不然的话...
Otherwise...
不然怎么样?
Otherwise what?
举起双手 立刻放开孩子
You put your hands in the air, and let go of that kid now.
- Peter 你没问题吧?  - 没问题
- Peter, you good?  - Yeah, I'm good.
带他出去
Get him outta here.
记得我说过我们还没完吗?
Remember when I said we weren't done?
现在完了
Now we're done.
第一个回合
All right, the first time out,
Summers操纵Griffith偷Jacoby的钱
Summers manipulates Griffith to steal from Jacoby.
然后反将一军
Then she turns it around.
让Jacoby去找Griffith
She steers Jacoby towards Griffith.
对于她倒是说得通
Well, it makes sense on her part.
Jacoby去杀Griffith 把自己搞进监狱
Jacoby tries to kill Griffith, lands himself in jail,
而她带着钱安然离去
and she walks with the money.
依然没有指向Summers的
There's still no physical evidence
确凿证据
pointing toward Summers.
只有心智操控
Only psychological manipulation.
我们有什么办法?
What's our best option?
要么把钱找到 但估计藏得很好
Find the money, which is probably well hidden,
要么让Summers招供
or get a confession out of Summers,
这个更不可能了
which is all the more unlikely.
未必
Not necessarily.
总有一剂药可为良方
There's always a solution.
此处"solution"双关 既指药剂 又指解决办法
很高兴看到你气色有起色
I'm glad to see you're feeling better.
我对生活有了一种新视角
I got a new perspective on things.
跟我讲讲
Tell me about that.
我承认我不知道
Well, I can admit that I don't know
自己是否能控制本能冲动
if I can control my natural impulses,
但失控并未让我感到无助
but that lack of control doesn't make me feel helpless.
那你感到什么?
How does it make you feel, then?
自由
Free.
因此你承认你仍旧乐于犯罪
So you admit you still like to commit criminal acts.
事实上 我现在就要犯上一桩
I'm gonna commit one right now, as a matter of fact.
钱在哪里?
Where's the money?
你让Griffith偷的那些
The money you had Griffith steal.
你可以接着装傻
You can play dumb
医生 但好景不长的
all you want, Doctor, but it won't last long.
药很快就要生效了
The drugs will take effect soon.
不可能
That's not possible.
我拿开了水瓶 自己倒的水
I removed the water bottles and poured it myself.
那你会发现重新塑封瓶盖是多么容易
You'd be surprised how easy it is to reseal a plastic lid.
开始抠指甲了 医生?
Are you picking your fingernails, Doctor?
也就是说你很紧张
'Cause that would mean you're nervous.
- 你紧张吗?  - 你不能这么对我
- Are you nervous?  - You can't do this to me.
告诉我钱在哪
Tell me where the money is.
联邦调查局永远也别想找到
The FBI will never find it.
是啊 他们找不到
No, they won't.
但毕竟我可是个罪犯
I am a criminal, after all.
你帮我意识到这点 多谢了 医生
You helped me realize that, so thank you, Doctor.
我需要的只是...
All I need from you...
招供
is a confession.
你准备好 我们就开始吧
I'm ready to begin when you are.
Mara Summers医生 现在以
Dr. Mara Summers, you're under arrest
盗窃 私藏违禁药物以及渎职罪逮捕你
for theft, possession of illegal narcotics, and malpractice.
有证据吗?
On the basis of what?
你的招供
Your confession.
我知道Shane Jacoby偷了钱
I knew Shane Jacoby stole that money.
那个白痴额头上就跟
Idiot may as well have had "guilty"
烙着"有罪"俩字儿似的
tattooed across his forehead.
我跟踪他到他藏钱的金库
I followed him to the vault where he hid the cash.
这是非法的 你们对我下药了
This isn't legal. You drugged me.
我想你说的是你不小心对自己下了药
I think you mean you accidentally drugged yourself.
我们要对你做一个毒样检查
We're gonna do a tox screen on you that's probably gonna match
结果可能跟你给Neal下的毒完全一样
the unprescribed cocktail you dosed Neal with at his session.
而你再次试图对我下药时 Peter会提出
And in trying to drug me again, Peter's going with
你可能不小心换错了瓶子
the theory that you made the mistake of switching bottles,
害了自己
inadvertently harming yourself.
差不多是这样 带她走
That sounds about right. Take her.
女士
Ma'am.
你应该知道你永远
You do understand you'll never be
也跳不出罪犯的圈子了
anything more than what you are.
但至少我是自由的
But at least I'm free.
我就能跟你说这么多了
Which is more than I can say for you.
跟我走
Come with me.
就这样? 我清白了?
So that's it? I'm in the clear?
由于你当时所处的精神状态
The Bureau is not pressing any charges
联邦调查局不打算起诉你
due to the psychological duress you were under at the time.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 谢谢你  - 没事 应该的
- Thank you.  - Yeah, of course.
不 不 多谢你告诉我 我们这种人
No, no, thank you for showing me that guys like us
也能有所改变
can be more than what we were.
好运
Good luck.
看来他感觉好多了
Seems like he's feeling better.
是啊 你呢?
Yeah. How about you?
再次结案的感觉如何?
How does it feel to close a case again?
我不确定是否算结案
I'm not so sure the case is closed.
Summers终于肯松口告诉我们她把200万藏哪里了
Summers cracked and told us where she hid the $2 million,
但我们去找的时候却没找到
but when we went to retrieve it, it wasn't there.
至少我们弄到了她的招供
Hmm, good thing we got a confession.
你是说这个归我了?
You're telling me I can have this?
把它当作我那天晚上
Consider it an apology
对你说的话的道歉吧
for all the things I said the other night.
忠言逆耳而已
They were things I needed to hear.
是时候重建帝国了 老朋友
It's time to rebuild the empire, my friend.
友情提醒 钞票做了标记
Word of caution. The bills are marked.
每一美元我还是可以换来50美分的 仍是一笔不错的收获
I can get 50 cents on the dollar. Still a pretty good haul.
我还以为小菜一碟呢
I figured it wouldn't be a problem.
这是从你自己直系猫咪探长
This is illegally obtained contraband from one
手上的案子里非法搞来的
of your very own suit's Federal investigations.
你为什么要拿?
So why'd you take it?
因为它就在那儿
Because it was there.
总有一天我要找到合适的说法
One day I'll find the right words,
一定要言简意赅
and they will be simple.
- 凯鲁亚克说的  - 没错
- Kerouac.  - Yeah.
不能更言简意赅了
Can't get much simpler than that.
对于咱们这样的来说就不是了
Not for guys like us.
咱们这样的? 你要回归老日子了?
Guys like us? You coming back to the life?
那你第一步如何打算?
So what's your first plan of action?
改变战局
Change the state of play.
我有太多主子了
I've been serving too many masters.
我受够了当每个人的玩偶
I'm through being everyone's puppet.
Hagen 联邦调查局...
Hagen, the FBI...
你到底计划脱离哪一方呢?
Which strings, exactly, do you plan on cutting?
一旦时机成熟...
When the time comes...
统统再见
all of them.